Louis Cohn-Haft
Smith College Archives
This collection is organized into six series: SERIES I. BIOGRAPHY SERIES II. TEACHING SERIES III. HISTORY DEPARTMENT SERIES IV. COLLEGE ADMINISTRATION SERIES V. PROFESSIONAL ACTIVITIES SERIES VI. OVERSIZE MATERIALS The records are open for research according to the regulations of the Smith College Archives without any additional restrictions. The Louis Cohn-Haft Papers were donated by Louis Cohn-Haft in 1989. Smith College -- Faculty Cohn-Haft, Louis, 1919-2012.
- Louis Cohn-Haft Papers, Series I: Biography 1950-1988; Cohn-Haft, Louis, 1919 - 2012; RG 42_cohn-haft; 2 boxes (.9 linear ft.); 1950-1988 4 boxes (2 linear feet) Smith College Archives Northampton, MA; Correspondence, ephemera, newspaper clippings, syllabi, photographs, typescripts, and handwritten manuscripts of Louis Cohn-Haft, professor of history.
  Contains materials related to Cohn-Haft's leisure activities including his extensive experience acting and singing in dramatic performances. His interest in liberal politics is well documented, showing his active support for a variety of causes, most notably the anti-Vietnam War movement. Photographs are also housed in this series
- Series II: Teaching 1950-1988
  Documents Cohn-Haft's academic teaching career from his early years at Columbia University through his retirement from Smith in 1987. The series also includes syllabi from his courses that span decades. Materials relating to his part-time work at Hartford College for Women are also included.
- Series III: History Department 1950-1988
  Contains materials relating to the Smith College History Department. This includes departmental meeting minutes, curriculum discussions, interdepartmental social events, and plans for lectures sponsored by the department.
- Series IV: College Administration 1950-1988
  Features Cohn-Haft's interaction and involvement with the Smith administration and his work at a college-wide level. Materials include: notices for faculty meetings, documentation on general curriculum requirements, service on various policy committees and discussion of the college's tenure and promotion policies.
- Series V: Professional Activities 1950-1988
  Houses materials relating to Cohn-Haft's professional activities besides teaching, both at Smith and beyond. Includes lectures and speeches for events such as Smith Mobile and the Alumnae College, involvement in the general Smith community, memberships in historical organizations and independent research. A few materials regarding his writings are also located here.
- Series VI: Oversized 1950-1988
  Contains a handmade poster created for a fundraising event.
- Series I: Biography
  - general (Box 718.3, Folder 1)
  - charity work, 1957-1961 (Box 718.3, Folder 2)
  - dramatics, 1956-1961 (Box 718.3, Folder 3)
  - dramatics, 1962-79, undated (Box 718.3, Folder 4)
  - friends and aquaintainces, 1960-1987 (Box 718.3, Folder 5)
  - leisure activities, 1956-1969 (Box 718.3, Folder 6)
  - photographs (Box 718.3, Folder 7)
  - politics - 1952:Presidential Election (Box 718.3, Folder 8)
  - politics - communism, 1952-1974 (Box 718.3, Folder 9)
  - politics - Greece, 1967 (Box 718.3, Folder 10)
  - politics - Student Strike, May 1970 (Box 718.3, Folder 11)
  - politics - Vietnam War, 1966-1969 (Box 718.3, Folder 12)
  - politics - miscellaneous, 1952-1972 (Box 718.3, Folder 13)
  - travel, 1957 (Box 718.3, Folder 14)
  - Athena Iris Caprano, wife, 1961-1962 (Box 718.3, Folder 15)
  - miscellaneous (Box 718.3, Folder 16)
- Series II: Teaching
  - Columbia University
    - calendars, 1951, undated (Box 718.4, Folder 1)
    - college administration, 1952-1953, 1965 (Box 718.4, Folder 2)
    - syllabi - HST 5, 1950-1952 (Box 718.4, Folder 3)
    - syllabi - HST 6, 1951-1953 (Box 718.4, Folder 4)
    - events, 1951-1953 (Box 718.4, Folder 5)
    - personal correspondence, 1952-1953, undated (Box 718.4, Folder 6)
  - Hartford College for Women
    - general (Box 718.4, Folder 7)
    - administration, 1976-1984 (Box 718.4, Folder 8)
    - events, 1966, 1982 (Box 718.4, Folder 9)
  - Smith College
    - career: promotions, 1956, 1958 (Box 718.4, Folder 10)
    - career: sabbaticals, 1969-1983 (Box 718.4, Folder 11)
    - career: Symposium in Honor of Cohn-Haft, 1987 (Box 718.4, Folder 12)
    - career: retirement, 1987 (Box 718.4, Folder 13)
    - career: Miscellaneous (Box 718.4, Folder 14)
    - classes: general (Box 718.4, Folder 15)
    - classes: Schedules, 1952-1954, 1975-1987 (Box 718.4, Folder 16)
    - classes: Course Syllabi - HST 12, 1954-1956 (Box 718.4, Folder 17)
    - classes: Course Syllabi - HST 12, 1956-1958 (Box 718.4, Folder 18)
    - classes: Course Syllabi - HST 12, 1958-1960 (Box 718.4, Folder 19)
    - classes: Course Syllabi - HST 12, 1960-1962 (Box 718.5, Folder 1)
    - classes: Course Syllabi - HST 12, 1962-1964 (Box 718.5, Folder 2)
    - classes: Course Syllabi - HST 12, 1964-1966 (Box 718.5, Folder 3)
    - classes: Course Syllabi - HST 12, 1966-1969, 1986 (Box 718.5, Folder 4)
    - classes: Course Syllabi - HST 101, 1986-1987 (Box 718.5, Folder 5)
    - classes: Course Syllabi - HST 201-203, 1961, 1981 (Box 718.5, Folder 6)
    - classes: Guest Lectures, 1984-1985 (Box 718.5, Folder 7)
    - classes:Junior Year Abroad Florence (Box 718.5, Folder 8)
- Series III: History Department
  - general (Box 718.5, Folder 9)
  - curriculum, 1965-1986 (Box 718.5, Folder 10)
  - events - general, 1955-1984 (Box 718.5, Folder 11)
    - events - departmental, 1955-1983 (Box 718.5, Folder 12)
  - meeting minutes, 1955-1983 (Box 718.5, Folder 13)
- Series IV: College Administration
  - general (Box 719, Folder 1)
  - colleagues, 1968-1988 (Box 719, Folder 2)
  - committees, 1957-1985 (Box 719, Folder 3)
  - committees - Marshals, 1977-1983 (Box 719, Folder 4)
  - curriculum, 1965-1974 (Box 719, Folder 5)
  - faculty meetings, 1960-1975 (Box 719, Folder 6)
  - finances, 1957-1982 (Box 719, Folder 7)
  - office, 1957-1987 (Box 719, Folder 8)
  - tenure and promotion, 1960-1976 (Box 719, Folder 9)
- Series V. Professional Activities
  - Alumnae College, 1978-1986 (Box 719, Folder 10)
  - American Association of University Professors, 1969, 1979 (Box 719, Folder 11)
  - American Historical Association, 1968, 1978 (Box 719, Folder 12)
  - American Philological Association, 1964, 1975 (Box 719, Folder 13)
  - Association of Ancient Historians, 1960-1976 (Box 719, Folder 14)
  - books and periodicals collection, 1966-1987 (Box 719, Folder 15)
  - class reunions and college clubs, 1959-1988 (Box 719, Folder 16)
  - events - general, 1954-1987 (Box 719, Folder 17)
  - Father's Day, 1954-1967 (Box 719, Folder 18)
  - invitations, 1967-1988, undated (Box 719, Folder 19)
  - lectures and speeches, 1956-1986, undated (Box 719, Folder 20)
  - NDEA History Institute, 1967, 1969 (Box 719, Folder 21)
  - organizations - miscellaneous (Box 719, Folder 22)
  - Smith Mobile, 1958 (Box 719, Folder 23)
  - Sophia Circus, 1958-1961 (Box 719, Folder 24)
  - 7writings, 1951-1981 (Box 719, Folder 25)
- Series VI: Oversize
  - poster (Box *)